<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata>
<idinfo>
<citation>
<citeinfo>
<title>Non-spatial table GeoMaterialDict, part of Metadata Template</title>
</citeinfo>
</citation>
<descript>
<supplinf>Non-spatial table GeoMaterialDict is part of GeMS.gdb, a composite dataset that conforms to "GeMS (Geologic Map Schema)--a standard format for the digital publication of geologic maps", available at http://ngmdb.usgs.gov/Info/standards/GeMS/.</supplinf>
</descript>
<accconst>None</accconst>
<useconst>None</useconst>
</idinfo>
<dataqual>
<attracc>
<attraccr>Confidence that a feature exists and confidence that a feature is correctly identified are described in per-feature attributes ExistenceConfidence and IdentityConfidence.</attraccr>
</attracc>
<posacc>
<horizpa>
<horizpar>Estimated accuracy of horizontal location is given on a per-feature basis by attribute LocationConfidenceMeters. Values are expected to be correct within a factor of 2.  A LocationConfidenceMeters value of -9 or -9999 indicates that no value has been assigned.</horizpar>
</horizpa>
</posacc>
<lineage></lineage>
</dataqual>
<eainfo>
<detailed>
<enttyp>
<enttypl>GeoMaterialDict</enttypl>
<enttypd>Non-spatial table that provides values of GeoMaterial, placed in a hierarchy, and their definitions. For further information, see Appendix A in GeMS documentation, available at http://ngmdb.usgs.gov/Info/standards/GeMS.</enttypd>
<enttypds>GeMS</enttypds>
</enttyp>
<attr>
<attrlabl>OBJECTID</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Internal feature number</attrdef>
<attrdefs>Esri</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Unrepresentable domain.</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>HierarchyKey</attrlabl>
<attrdef>String that records hierarchical structure. Has form nn-nn-nn, nnn-nnn, or similar. Numeric, left-padded with zeros, dash-delimited. Each HierarchyKey fragment of each row MUST be the same length to allow text-based sorting of table entries.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>GeMS</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Unrepresentable domain.</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>GeoMaterial</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Categorization of map unit based on lithologic and genetic character, term selected from NGMDB standard term list defined in Appendix A of GeMS documentation, available at http://ngmdb.usgs.gov/Info/standards/GeMS..</attrdef>
<attrdefs>GeMS</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<codesetd>
<codesetn>GeoMaterial Dictionary</codesetn>
<codesets>GeMS</codesets>
</codesetd>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>IndentedName</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Name with addition of leading spaces to help show rank within a hierarchical list.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>GeMS</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Unrepresentable domain.</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>Definition</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Plain-language definition.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>GeMS</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Unrepresentable domain.</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
</detailed>
</eainfo>
<metainfo>
<metstdn>FGDC Content Standard for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
<metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
<mettc>local time</mettc>
</metainfo>
</metadata>
