<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata>
<idinfo>
<citation>
<citeinfo>
<title>Non-spatial table Glossary, part of Metadata Template</title>
</citeinfo>
</citation>
<descript>
<supplinf>Non-spatial table Glossary is part of GeMS.gdb, a composite dataset that conforms to "GeMS (Geologic Map Schema)--a standard format for the digital publication of geologic maps", available at http://ngmdb.usgs.gov/Info/standards/GeMS/.</supplinf>
</descript>
<accconst>None</accconst>
<useconst>None</useconst>
</idinfo>
<dataqual>
<attracc>
<attraccr>Confidence that a feature exists and confidence that a feature is correctly identified are described in per-feature attributes ExistenceConfidence and IdentityConfidence.</attraccr>
</attracc>
<posacc>
<horizpa>
<horizpar>Estimated accuracy of horizontal location is given on a per-feature basis by attribute LocationConfidenceMeters. Values are expected to be correct within a factor of 2.  A LocationConfidenceMeters value of -9 or -9999 indicates that no value has been assigned.</horizpar>
</horizpa>
</posacc>
<lineage></lineage>
</dataqual>
<eainfo>
<detailed>
<enttyp>
<enttypl>Glossary</enttypl>
<enttypd>Non-spatial table that, for certain fields (including all Type fields, Confidence fields, and GeneralLithology), lists the terms that populate these fields, term definitions, and sources for definitions.</enttypd>
<enttypds>GeMS</enttypds>
</enttyp>
<attr>
<attrlabl>OBJECTID</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Internal feature number</attrdef>
<attrdefs>Esri</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Unrepresentable domain.</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>Glossary_ID</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Primary key.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>GeMS</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Arbitrary string. Values should be unique within this database.</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>Term</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Plain-language word for a concept. Values must be unique within database as a whole.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>GeMS</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Unrepresentable domain.</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>Definition</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Plain-language definition.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>GeMS</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Unrepresentable domain.</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>DefinitionSourceID</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Source of definition; foreign key to DataSources.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>GeMS</attrdefs>
</attr>
</detailed>
</eainfo>
<metainfo>
<metstdn>FGDC Content Standard for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
<metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
<mettc>local time</mettc>
</metainfo>
</metadata>
