<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><metadata><idinfo><citation><citeinfo><title>Metadata Template</title></citeinfo></citation><descript><supplinf>GeMS.gdb is a composite geodataset that conforms to "GeMS (Geologic Map Schema)--a standard format for the digital publication of geologic maps", available at http://ngmdb.usgs.gov/Info/standards/GeMS/. Metadata records associated with each element within the geodataset contain more detailed descriptions of their purposes, constituent entities, and attributes. An OPEN shapefile versions of the dataset is also available. It consists of shapefiles, DBF files, and delimited text files and retains all information in the native geodatabase, but some programming will likely be necessary to assemble these components into usable formats. These metadata were prepared with the aid of script GeMS_FGDC1_Arc10.py, version of version of 8 May 2023.</supplinf></descript><accconst>None</accconst><useconst>None</useconst></idinfo><dataqual><attracc><attraccr>Confidence that a feature exists and confidence that a feature is correctly identified are described in per-feature attributes ExistenceConfidence and IdentityConfidence.</attraccr></attracc><posacc><horizpa><horizpar>Estimated accuracy of horizontal location is given on a per-feature basis by attribute LocationConfidenceMeters. Values are expected to be correct within a factor of 2.  A LocationConfidenceMeters value of -9 or -9999 indicates that no value has been assigned.</horizpar></horizpa></posacc><lineage><srcinfo><srccite><citeinfo><title>Federal Geographic Data Committee [prepared for the Federal Geographic Data Committee by the U.S. Geological Survey], 2006, FGDC Digital Cartographic Standard for Geologic Map Symbolization: Reston, Va., Federal Geographic Data Committee Document Number FGDC-STD-013-2006, 290 p., 2 plates.</title><onlink>https://ngmdb.usgs.gov/fgdc_gds/geolsymstd.php</onlink></citeinfo></srccite><srccitea>FGDC-STD-013-2006</srccitea></srcinfo></lineage></dataqual><eainfo><overview><eaover>Database GeMS.gdb contains the following elements: non-spatial table DescriptionOfMapUnits (0 rows); non-spatial table DataSources (1 rows); non-spatial table RepurposedSymbols (0 rows); non-spatial table StandardLithology (0 rows); non-spatial table MiscellaneousMapInformation (0 rows); non-spatial table GeoMaterialDict (101 rows); non-spatial table Glossary (44 rows); feature dataset GeologicMap which contains feature class MapUnitPolys (0 features), feature class DataSourcePolys (0 features), feature class MapUnitOverlayPolys (0 features), feature class OverlayPolys (0 features), feature class ContactsAndFaults (0 features), feature class GeologicLines (0 features), feature class CartographicLines (0 features), feature class IsoValueLines (0 features), feature class OrientationPoints (0 features), feature class GeochronPoints (0 features), feature class FossilPoints (0 features), feature class Stations (0 features), and feature class GenericPoints (0 features); feature dataset CorrelationOfMapUnits which contains feature class CMUMapUnitPolys (0 features), feature class CMULines (0 features), and feature class CMUPoints (0 features); feature dataset CrossSectionA which contains feature class CSAMapUnitPolys (0 features), feature class CSAContactsAndFaults (0 features), and feature class CSAOrientationPoints (0 features).</eaover><eadetcit>Detailed descriptions of entities, attributes, and attribute values are given in metadata for constituent elements of the database. See also "GeMS (Geologic Map Schema)--a standard format for the digital publication of geologic maps", available at http://ngmdb.usgs.gov/Info/standards/GeMS/.</eadetcit></overview></eainfo><metainfo><metstdn>FGDC Content Standard for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn><metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv><mettc>local time</mettc></metainfo></metadata>